that is, they have now created
то есть они создали сейчас в мире
such a picture in the world and in Europe that, like
картину такую и в Европе что типа
Kadyrov and the Chechens, Kadyrov’s people attacked
Кадыров и чеченцы кадыровцы напали на
Ukraine and Zelensky,
Украину и и Зеленский не может с ним
together with America and NATO, cannot cope with
вместе с Америкой и НАТО справиться с
Kadyrov, I’ll make such a picture Gordon has
Кадыровым такую картину сделаю Гордон
generally dispersed there Kadyrov’s enemy is
вообще разошёлся там враг Кадырова
Kadyrov’s personal enemy what kind of enemy  Kadyrov's
личный враг Кадырова какой враг Кадырова
enemy, a Chechen can only be
врагом чеченец может быть только
Russia Hello Hello, where are you
России Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
from? With Grozny some
откуда С Грозным какой-то
Streamer  Well, yes, the little one understood what you
Стример Ну да небольшой понял о чём
were talking about,
общаетесь
and about everything about religion, you are interested in
да о всяком о религии увлекаетесь
Ancient Germanic religion, yes Well, yes,
Древне германской религии да Ну да
religions are Ancient Well, not only Ancient
религии Древне Ну не только Древне
Germanic Well, I see you have a young
германской Ну я смотрю у вас там моло
Torah there, it was interesting there Are you
Тора там вальгала там интересно А вы
interested in this just on a say-so
увлекаетесь это просто на скажем ческом
level or are you there  perform rituals no,
уровне или вы там обряды проводите нет
I haven’t moved on to rituals yet. And
на обряды я как бы пока не перешёл А
where are you from? I’m from Grozny, okay,
откуда вы сами Я из Грозного Да ладно
that’s a joke. No, I just don’t
это прикол Да нет я просто сейчас не
live in Grozny now, of course, but I moved
живу конечно же в грозной а переехал
two years ago.  where do you live in
года два назад то где живёте в
Lithuania Cool And who is Chechen by nationality
Литве Прикольно А по национальности кто
Tell me Ichkeria will be free
чеченец Скажите Ичкерия будет свободной
in
по
Chechen
чеченский
sha no you are not
ша не вы не
Chechen You can now watch my
чеченец Вы можете сейчас посмотреть мой
channel if it is what kind of Anti-Terror
канал если хо он какой Антитеррор
chri it is now
чри сейчас
Yes indeed there is
Да действительно есть
cool I don’t know there you said
прикольно Я же не знаю там сказал Ты
in Chechen  or did I hear you just
по-чеченски или я слышал ты ног толь
say Yes, it’s so cool, yes there is Stream
сказал Да так прикольно да есть Стрим
Let’s talk about what we would call the state in
Давай поговори как бы мы государство на
our own language, but yes, yes there’s also a song
своём языке называли но да да ещ песня
Come on, you're an interesting character, it's
Давай всё ты интересный персонаж сбой
a glitch, let's talk,
поговорим
let's pony yourself stream what you Well, you
давай пони сам стримишь что ты Ну
understand that you are a public figure That
понимаешь что ты публичная личность То
is, you are not afraid to talk super
есть ты не боишься разговаривать супер
which side do you
какую сторону ты получается
support in the Ichkerian I
поддерживаешь в ичкерийского
understand Yes, interesting Listen, how many
понял Да интересно Слушай а вот сколько
Chechens do you estimate are outside the
чеченцев находятся за пределами
Russian Federation?  who
Российской Федерации тех которые вот
left because of persecution Well,
выехали из-за преследований Ну потому
because they are for a free Ichkeri Well,
что они за свободную ичкери Ну говорят
according to various estimates, about 300,000, but I
по разным оценкам около 300.000 но я
know
знаю
that  100,000 there are Ingush and
что штук 100.000 там это ингуши и
Dagestanis because every day they
дагестанцы потому что каждый день они
come and in the camp when I was. Listen,
приезжают и в лагере когда я был Слушай
wait one minute, you can wait a
подожди одна минутка можешь подождать
minute. I’ll change the flag now,
минуту Я сейчас флаг поменяю конечно
of course, friends,
Конечно друзья
236 people watching and 90 likes now, since there’s
236 смотрящих и 90 лайков сейчас раз
such a
такой
movement, there’s such a
движ раз пошла такая
booze, now we’ll
пьянка сейчас мы
make a complete
сделаем полный
Entourage
Антураж
clearly oops
чётко опа
and to the heroes
а героям
Slava
Слава
Oh I streamed under this flag I’m
О я под этим флагом э
streaming now to be honest I’m a little
стримил мне сейчас если честно чуть-чуть
ashamed I don’t have  such a
стыдно У меня у меня нету такого
Plaka Well, so I said, I dressed like that,
Плака Ну так я говорил я так одевал
I told the
говорил
Russians
русским
Yes, they were still afraid Hey, let’s come up to the number and we’ll
Да боялись ещё Эй давай номер подъедем
figure it out
разберёмся
Yes, so we
Да так
can We
что то може Мы
can we can send you a flag to Lithuania as a
те може мы тебе пришлём флаг в Литву в
gift as possible You can I’ll
подарок какой можно можно можно Всё я
write it all to you somewhere in the comments U
там напишу тебе где-то в комментариях У
we have our friends from Lithuania come from
нас есть приезжают наши друзья из Литвы
time to time we will print here those
время от времени мы тут напечатаем те
this is such a flag so that I
это такой флаг чтоб я
was I just didn’t know where to order it I was
был я просто не знал где его заказать
just interested I looked but here
просто интересовался смотрел но а у нас
in Ukraine  there are printing houses Yes, I’ll throw it all away, they
в Украине есть типографии Да всё скину
printed it, it’s healthy 2 s in short, in
напечатали он здоровый 2 с по короче в
general, we’ll decide it already yes Okay, how many according to
общем решим это уже да Окей сколько по
your estimates Yes people in euros Yes that will
твоим оценкам Да людей в евро Да которы
support Ikea
поддержит Икею
I don’t know the statistics, but they say that
я статистику не знаю но говорят что
300,000, according to various sources, left But
300.000 по разным данным выехало Но
somewhere, let’s say 50,000  or there are even more
где-то скажем так 50.000 или ещё больше
or fewer Ingush and Dagestanis
или меньше там ингуши и дагестанцы
who present themselves as Chechens and
которые представляются чеченцами и
receive asylum; there are a lot of them. Well,
получают убежище очень много таких Ну
that’s the number they support
вот такое количество а поддерживают
Ichkeri here is also somehow a little bit complicated,
ичкери тут тоже как-то чуть-чуть сложно
very because
очень потому что
they say they support Ichkeri for
они говорят ичкери поддерживают за
freedom, but in fact they are for another
свободу но по сути дела они за другую
Empire, for the Arab Islamic
Империю за арабскую исламскую
Empire, these are the events that
Империю эти те события которые у нас
happened here that brought this Ichkeri to, let’s
происходили которые эту ичкери довели до
say, maybe you know something like this  the
скажем так Может Вы знаете такое такой
term Imarat is called Yes, Khattab
термин Имарат называется Да там Хаттаб
was there then this yes yes this is a certain
был потом этот да да это некий
like this is a certain kind of region within the
как это некий как бы раон в составе сть
Caliphate yes yes yes yes yes they brought it to
Халифата да да да да да они довели до
this that is they changed
этого то есть они изменили Конституцию
Our Constitution of the year ninety-two, which our
нашу девяносто второго года которую наш
people adopted, is a secular Constitution,
народ принял это Конституция светская
completely Democratic, where religion is
полностью Демократическая где религия
separated from the state and as a result, in the
отделена от государства и в итоге В
year ninety-nine, well, some
девяносто девятом году Ну какая-то
group of people in the bushes in the mountains somewhere, a
группа людей в кустах в горах где-то
guerrilla group themselves take this
Партизанская группа сами берут эту
Constitution, change it, let’s say
Конституцию изменяют это скажем
this  article where the second article is the
так эту статью где вторая статья
only source of power in the Chechen
единственным источником власти чеченском
state is the Chechen people, they
государстве является чеченский народ они
take it, change it, the source of power
берут её изменяют источником власти
is the Koran and the Sunnah and the Koran and  The Sunnah is
является Коран и Сунна а Коран и Сунна
as if the Arabs are already dictating, they are
как бы это уже арабы диктуют они
commenting, they are interpreting and explaining, and
комментируют они трактуют и объясняют
so Mada did, he went to Ibn’s base, this is the
так и сделал Мада поехал к ибн базу это
Mufti of Saudi Arabia and asked
муфтий Саудовской Аравии и спрашивал у
him how to live for the Chechens and that is,
него как жить чеченцам и то есть
Igo and how would they now be half
Иго и как бы они теперь вот половина
more by Wait, wait, he is the Mufti, he
больше по Подожди подожди он муфтий он
It seems like he was the
же вроде был
president of the
президентом
time in which Maskhadov went to the
вре ин бас которому Масхадов поехал
president. Well, this was the mufti. I
президент А ну а это муфти был Всё я
thought that you were talking about the mufti Maskhadov. I’m
думал что муфти ты говоришь Масхадов Я
thinking about the same  he wasn’t a mufti, he wasn’t
же думаю о же не муфти был не не
Maskhadov, it’s like our president, against the
Масхадов как бы наш президент вот на
backdrop of all this, it’s like the
фоне этого всего как бы уже
radicalization of all this undercover
радикализации вот этой всей агентурной
work, well, Russia did a very good job
работы ну Россия очень хорошо поработала
for us when they left Yes, they switched to a
у нас когда они отошли Да перешли на
hybrid war, first they, like everyone else
гибридную войну сначала они как всё
now, we’ll take 2 hours
сейчас возьмём 2 часа
for yes yes  let's now establish a
по да да установим сейчас
constitutional order; the video was filmed
конституционный порядок видео снимали
now, let's return home and this whole
сейчас вернёмся домой и началась эта вся
mess started; it didn't work out for them. Yes, they did
заваруха не получилось у них Да сделали
an operation; they surrounded them, as it were, and forced them to
операцию окружили как бы и заставили
leave; and they just switched to a hybrid
уйти и они просто перешли на гибридную
war and typing tons  Islamic
войну и тоннами печатая исламскую
radical literature through their
радикальную литературу через свою
agents there are different names. By the way,
агентуру там разные имена Кстати у меня
on my channel you can also watch the
на канале можете тоже посмотреть
political situation among the Chechens.
политическая ситуация среди чеченцев
Today there is a very good video there is a complete
Сегодня очень хороший ролик там полный
analysis from beginning to end of a small
анализ от начала и до конца небольшой
short film. In short, I made it. In general,
короткий фильм Мой Короче я снял В общем
it’s like they left the radicals
такое дело они как бы отошли радикали
Zro  now he has the same temperament, he seems to be well
Зро сейчас тот же самый закал он как бы
with the Ukrainian, too, uh, in this video
ну с украинцем тоже ээ на этом видео
you will also find his video, he with the Ukrainian in an
найдёте тоже его ролик он с украинцем в
interview says that he is for the ninety-
интервью говорит что он за девяносто
second year of the Constitution and then
вторую года Конституцию а потом он
he gathers all the Europeans who are drowning for freedom, gathers them in Sweden and leads them in the Chechen language, that they generally united on the Constitution of 2002, that is, on these changes. That is, it’s already, as it were, well, the concept is being replaced, I sort of explain this question that this is the way we already passed Let's not get up to this rake anymore, agents are working everywhere now I was once in Kyiv there was just a press conference Zakayev was Uh, someone else should be from the Ingush  but I didn’t come from the Ingush then,
быть но не приехал о от ингушей тогда
in principle, I understand that at the
вот то в принципе я так понимаю что на
official level, at least,
официальном по крайней мере уровень
Zakayev supports a more secular
Закаев поддерживает более светскую
concept of the state Yes, at the official level Yes
концепцию государства Да на официальном
Like yes yes yes Well, you just see here it’s
Да Типа да да да Ну просто тут видите у
very difficult for you due to the fact that there are so
вас очень сложно из-за того что очень
many  different movements of very different
много разных течений очень разных групп
disparate groups and finding some common
разрозненных и найти какой-то общий
denominator for them is problematic, that
знаменатель под них ну проблематично то
is, there is no more Why because of religion,
есть нету больша Почему из-за религии
when the First War was there for everyone,
вот когда Первая война была у всех
someone smoked, someone drank, someone did their
кто-то курил кто-то там пил кто-то свой
namaz  did someone religious, they all
намаз делал кто-то религиозный был все
became one and such an Empire was forced to
стали и такую Империю короче заставили
leave. After that, what they did
уйти После этого они что сделали
was divided through religion into these currents,
разделили через религию на эти тече на э
they put an emphasis on it, and a war began among
сделали акцент И началась уже между
themselves, bloodshed to kill each other,
собой война кровопролитие друг друга
and at that moment, on three sides,
убивать и в этот момен с трёх сторон
every village  erasing from the face of the earth, they
каждое село стирая с лица земли они ни
never came face to face in battle with the
один раз не столкнулись лоб лоб в бою с
army, not once in the second war, they
армией ни разу во второй войне они
simply entered from three sides in the second war,
просто во второй войне зашли с трёх
erasing, they reached Grozny, they erased
сторон стирая дошли до Грозного стёрли
everything, all the Chechen  The republic was razed to
всё всю чеченскую Республику сравняли с
the ground, well, they bombed the aerial bomb there, they were
землёй ну так они бомбили авиабомба там
formidable, yes, they set up artillery for everyone, and every
грозными да да всем артиллерию ставили и
village left not a single house, not a single house,
село каждый дом ни одного ни один дом не
every word, every word, the entire
оставляет каждые сло всё сло ра всю
Chechen Republic was razed to the ground,
чеченскую Республику сравняли с землёй
in short, and like Putin went to Brussels.
короче и типа Путин поехал в Брюссель
Maybe you saw them there.  they want to build a
Может вы видели Там они хотят построить
caliphate. If you
халифат Если вы
come to Moscow, we will
буде Приезжайте в Москву мы вам кое-что
cut something short for you directly to parliament,
отрежем короче прямо в парламент
frankly to them  they also addressed In short,
откровенно им обратился и те Всё короче
and he erased us, let’s say like this Well,
и он стёр нас как бы скажем так вот тако
yes, on the world stage they did it, as it were, yes,
Ну да на мировой арене сделали как бы да
I am now explaining to people how we are all
я сейчас объясняю людям как бы мы все
Chechens
чеченцы
religion is not religion, there is no need to drag us into the
религия не религия не надо нас тащить в
caliphate, there is no need to drag us, we are
халифат не надо нас тащить Никуда мы
Chechens nowhere, wake up  us on this Yes, it’s
чеченцы проснитесь нас на этом Да мы как
like we all have our own religion, we’re like a Chechen
бы У всех своя религия мы как бы чеченец
- this is a nationality and not a religion, now
- это национальность а не религия сейчас
they’ve brought the youth at home to this point
они довели до того вот домашнюю молодёжь
under propaganda, what if not  Muslim,
под пропагандой что если не мусульманин
then you’re not a Chechen, that’s absurd. Islam began
то ты не чеченец это ж абсурд Ислам у
to spread in our country for 200 years at most,
нас 200 лет максимум распространяться
so those people who were 200 years
начал так те люди которые были 200 лет
ago are not Chechens or what, then
назад выходят не чеченцы что ли вы тогда
Who did you come from, that is, such a
От кого произошли то есть такая
schizophrenic degenerate situation, a
шизофреническая деградант ся ситуация
complete catastrophe, as if look, you’re
полнейшая катастрофу как бы смот э вы вы
going through  the same path that
проходите тот же самый путь что
European countries went through earlier
европейские страны прошли раньше потому
because Christianity is an earlier religion and
что христианство более ранняя религия и
it also went through these stages Yes, that’s
она вот эти этапы тоже прошла Да вот там
all there French and English You there You
всё там Француз и англичанин Вы там Вы
Christians You must go In short, to
христиане Вы должны идти Короче в
Palestine somewhere short of some kind there for a
палестину куда-то короче каких-то там за
gentleman like yes, they are also
господин типа да вот тоже сейчас
passing through now Well, the
проходит
mosque and recapture it because the
им Ну мечеть а отвоевать потому что
Judgment
Судный
Day of
денька
Tuka is taco, but you
Тука есть тако а
heard Just think about it, we are Chechens, in short, we
слышали Сам подумай мы чеченцы короче
are sitting surrounded by Russians in the bushes and
сидим в окружении русских в кустах и
we sing for
поём за
Jerusalem, this temple will be taken
Иерусалим этот храм будет взят
Uh mi
Уй ми
sme they continue to
сме там продолжают
act there and it’s kind of interesting
действовать причём как бы интересно да
if uh let’s say
если бы ээ скажем
uh these processes would take place there
ээ вот эти процессы э прошли б там
a little later Yes with Islam  Caucasus
немножко позже Да с Исламом на Кавказе
Yes, because in fact, Well, Islam
Да потому что фактически Ну Ислам поздно
reached there late, quite late, there were
туда дошёл довольно поздно там были в
basically such local beliefs Well, as
основном такие местные верования Ну как
if they were ordinary Yes, that was not the case, but they
бы обычные Да вот то не было но они
took Dagestan, Derbent is, well, well, well, the
Дагестан взяли Дербент это ну как бы ну
Derbent plain, yes, yes, yes, they
равнина Дербент да да да да они это
took it and, as it were  they didn’t go further into the mountains,
взяли и как бы дальше в горы не лезли
there was Islam since the 7th century. Well,
там был Ислам ещё с VII де века Ну
because Derbent, empires changed there,
потому что Дербент он там же менялись
and Timur and whoever you want
империи и там и Тимур и кто ни хочешь
came there. Yes, he’s on the Caspian Sea, on
приходил Да оно ж он на Каспии стоит на
par with the trade there  along the paths of the Great
равнение там на торговым путям Великий
Silk Road there was therefore
Шёлковый путь был поэтому
Yes, but we, as it were, did not pass to us
Да но мы как бы к нам он не не переходил
only 200-300 years ago through already When the
только 200-300 лет назад через уже Когда
Russian Empire arrived with the Tatars
Российская империя подъехала с татарами
Yes, as if I perceive the Russian Empire
Да как бы Российскую империю я
as Russian
воспринимаю как
-Tatar and Russian as if purely
русско-татарские и русские как бы чисто
Russian and the Tatars  they seem to know the Turkic
русские а татары знают как бы тюркский
language and among us there were already Kumyks,
язык и среди нас уже были кумыки которых
well, Timur brought these Turkic tribes, they are
Ну Тимур привёз это тюркские племена они
already ours  they knew their language and
уже наш язык знали свой знали и наш
knew ours and the Russians contacted us
знали и русские контактировали с нами
through the Tatars through the Kumyks who
через Татаров через кумыков которые
already know our language and how we
знают Уже наш язык и как бы у нас такой
had such a cultural exchange and they, through
культурный обмен прошёл и они через вот
this Islam, had already kind of spread
этот Ислам уже как бы распространили
this among us I read Yes, that’s exactly
среди нас этот Я читал Да что вот как
what  in those days when Russia came, the
раз в те времена когда вот Россия зашла
Kumyk language was such a
то кумыкский язык был на Кавказе таким
lingua franca in the Caucasus Well, like a common language for
Лингва Франка Ну типа общий язык для
many peoples Because its well, the Jurassic
многих народов Потому что его ну Юрский
language was not a Kumyk back then. Well, this
язык куками тогда они ещё не были Ну это
is Kipchak.  the group turns out to be like
это кипчак ся группа получается как
Kazakhs, like Crimean Tatars, they are Well,
казахи как крымские татары они Ну
yes, here’s an interesting question: before the
да вот такой интересный вопрос до
full-scale invasion of Ukraine
полномасштабного вторжения в Украину
in Europe, there were cases where Kadyrov
в Европе были случаи что там Кадыров
expelled people who were some kind of
выслал людей которые там какие-то
opposition journalists,
оппозиционные журналисты оппозиционные
Chechen opposition bloggers there in order to somehow
блогеры чеченские там чтобы их как-то
neutralize them, like the same Tumso
нейтрализовать вроде на того же тумсо
was there an assassination attempt or was there a staging, well,
было покушение или там инсценировка ну
something happened. That’s how safe it is now with this.
что-то было Вот насколько сейчас с этим
Well, I think now they
Ну я думаю сейчас как бы у них более
’ll have more difficulties, but then again,
трудности будут но опять же
if it’s like  do something now the
если тут как бы что-то сейчас делать
borders are now strictly guarded as if
границы жёстко сейчас охраняются как бы
now I think it’s more risky it
сейчас я думаю более рискованно это
will be hard a little
будет тяжело чуть-чуть
bit safer than then I think now
чуть безопаснее чем тогда я думаю сейчас
then they paid them
тогда они что им что там заплатили
dollars one went killed got on a
доллары один поехал убил сел на там
bus there for a plane and home and flew  to
автобус на самолёт и домой и прилетел в
Russia yes yes yes yes And no problems like
Россию да да да да И никаких проблем как
now in Germany then they killed
сечас рнии в Германии тогда убили это
him I think they caught him right away and exchanged him
Его по-моему поймали сразу да и поменяли
for I think some Jew now I don’t
на по-моему еврея какого-то сейчас не
remember him
помню его
like but  for example, with this with
как а вот например с этим с
some political movements in
политическими какими-то движениями в
Europe Yes, besides there, besides
Европе Да кроме вот там кроме вот
Zakayev, there are some other personalities.
закаева какие-то есть ещё личности
Well, there are
какие-то Ну есть
democrats, well, they are
демократи ну они как бы
now, let’s say, at some
сейчас скажем так на каком-то
state government office through all these media
государственном УВ через вот эти все СМИ
they are not  they are promoting,
их не пиарят
I don’t know why, but this is purely
я не знаю почему но это чисто
Democratic, as it were, the Chechen
Демократическая как бы чеченская
Democratic
демократическая
Party is purely a people’s initiative, they
партия чисто Народная инициатива они
work in YouTube, they broadcast, they communicate with
работают в ютубера вещают общаются с
people, they try to somehow
людьми пытаются как-то то же самое эти
explain the same issues to people, Hussein Ihav
вопросы разъяснить людям Хусейн ихав
is  like this now I don’t know whether he is the
есть такой сейчас я не знаю он является
main one of this party or not, but it’s as
ли Ну главным этой партии или нет но как
if he was there too And these are the things that seem
бы он тоже там был И вот такие дела идут
to be going on for Kaya now, like this well, the
как бы за Каю сейчас как бы вот этот ну
acting
актёрскую
media These are the things He’s all from there, he’s an
СМИ Вот эти дела Все он же оттуда он
actor too, as it were  he’s busy in this and seems to be
актёр тоже как бы в этом занят и как бы
paying all the attention to himself, but the Chechens
всё внимание на себя уделяет но чеченцы
don’t support him at all. Well, you
его не поддерживают абсолютно Ну тут тут
see here. Yes, the problem is that,
видите Да тут проблема в том что
uh, for the West, Yes, we need some people to
ээ для Запада Да нужны какие-то лица
represent him. And yet,
которые бы представляли Да и всё-таки
no matter how he is, he’s still  - after all, he was
как бы не было он всё-таки был там
the Prime Minister there and the Prime Minister  Ichkeri he was Like,
премьером да Премьер ичкери он был Вроде
yes, that is, he’s still some kind of
да то есть он всё равно какая-то
political figure who you can kind of,
политическая фигура которую можно как бы
well, because for example, here you are conditionally
ну об потому что например вот ты условно
Yes, bring you with some member of the
Да привести тебя и с каким-то депутатом
European Parliament. Here’s some dude like
европарламента Вот какой-то чувак типа
came and like Who is this anyway  yes,
пришёл и типа А кто это вообще да
that’s why it’s
поэтому
difficult here yes And listen, you know
тут тут сложно да А слушай ты вот знаешь
about such a forum of free peoples in
про такой форум свободных народов в
Russia dadada yes where he participated there is
России дадада да где он участвовал там
some kind of Kasparov Yes also not no Kasparov
Каспаров какой-то Да тоже не не Каспаров
there well well others Yes there are different ones here these
там ну ну другие Да разные есть вот эти
too about uh these Uh  how are they
тоже про э эти Ээ как они
uh different organizations that advocate
ээ разные организации которые выступают
for the independence of their republics so they are a
за независимость своих республик так они
league League of Free Nations maybe
лига лига свободных Наций может быть
Ukrainian yes yes Well this is a forum of free
украинская да да Ну это форум свободных
peoples of Russia yes yes yes I heard there for
народов России да да да я слышал Там за
kae I think he once spoke there
кае по-моему как-то там выступал там у
they had a meeting in  In Poland, in my opinion, or
них были совещание в Польше по-моему или
there they conduct it in different in different places.
там они в разных в разных
But don’t monitor this
проводят А вот ты не монитори так эту
organization like that. No, the organization itself.
организацию Нет саму организацию
No, I don’t have a lot of trust in this,
Нет у меня мало как бы доверия этим ещ
and
как бы а
why? Well, again, these are supposedly
почему Ну опять же вот эти как бы
oppositionists  in general, Well, I think that
оппозиционеры в общем Ну я считаю что
they are financed by Russia, as if for
они финансируются Россией как бы за
preservation, as if it acts destructively,
сохранение как бы деструктивно действует
as it
как бы
were, but in the World Cup it
да А в ЧМ деструктивно
acts destructively. For example, if there is zaka there, then
действует Например если зака там то
again
опять
for me the rest of the forum is the same as
же для меня остальной форум такой же как
if it were a performance, again, don’t monitor,
бы спектакль я опять же не монитори
maybe I’m wrong  I can about
может быть я ошибаться могу насчёт
others, again, I Why am I not
других опять же я Почему мне не
interested because you
интересно потому что имени
understand the name Look, if on behalf of
высту понимаешь Смотри если от имени
Ichkeri Yes he speaks for the Kais Yes, so where are the
ичкери Да выступает за каев Да так где
other groups Nobody forbids
другие группы Никто же не запрещает там
other groups there to also, as it were, promote
другим группам тоже как бы продвигать
your concepts are somewhere here, these forums
свои концепции где-то тут вот эти форум
What is the point Yes, because I monitor
В чём суть Да его потому что я монитори
I know people
Я знаю людей
from there with some of them I made
оттуда с некоторыми делал
videos The point is that
видеоролики Суть в том что вот
Chechnya was essentially the only one coming out of
Чечня она по сути одна выходила из из
Russia, Tatarstan also tried it and
России ещё Татарстан пробовал да и из-за
because  it wasn’t enough, yes Russia crushed
того что мало было да Россия задавила
Russia crushed so when the Soviet
Россия задавила поэтому когда Советский
Union collapsed there were 14 republics and what should
Союз распадался 14 республик потта и что
Russia do if there was only one there then we
России уже сделать если бы одна там была
could have done something else like this and
то мо може что-то ещё бы сделали так и
here at the moment X It will be necessary for more than one
тут в момент X Нужно будет чтобы не одна
some republic was moving and
какая-то республика двигалась а очень
moving a lot and already have to develop,
много двигалась и уже вырабатывать да
plus we need to develop some
плюс нужны какие-то уже вырабатывать
understandings on how to live further Yes, because
понимания Как жить дальше Да потому что
there, for example, the Tatars and Bashkortos
есть например там у татар и башкорто
have some claims against each other already,
есть какие-то претензии друг к другу уже
and the Chechens and Ingush have some  -
да у чеченцев и ингушей есть какие-то
also there, uh, and they’re doing it on purpose, they’re
тоже там ээ причём специально да делают
inflating it, that’s where Russia took
раздувают вот там Россия забрали у
part of the territory from Ingushetia and transferred it to
Ингушетии часть территории передали в
Chechnya, that is, they’re doing it, uh, on the principle of
Чечню да то есть делают ээ по принципу
share power, yes  In order for the
разделяй власт да Для того чтобы ээ не
gaze of all these peoples to be turned, as it were, not on Moscow,
на Москву был обращён как бы взгляд всех
but at each other so that they
этих народов А друг на друга чтобы они
gnaw at the Vainakhs, these are the Ingush,
грызли вот вайнахов это ж и ингуши
the Wars and the Chechens, the Wars, and from
Войнах и чеченцы Войнах да
scratch they made a melting pot from
на пустом месте сделали таю на пустом
scratch, they made two peoples and then
месте сделали два народа и потом ещё и
poisoned them  To be honest, it was as if we were
травили их Если честно мы как бы были
one people, with the same customs, we
одним народом одними обычаями жили
always lived as if in tribes, but
всегда как бы ну племенами да
separately, as if understanding each other,
обособленно как бы понимая друг друга
calling ourselves our people, our
называя себя нашими людьми нашей
culture, well, howl
культурой ну вой
if only
бы да бы
yes Well, the Russian Empire first made
Ну Российская империя сначала сделала
some kind of territory there for us, then the
какую-то Там территорию у нас потом
Soviet Union made Chechen Ingushetia out of it,
сделала из неё Советский Союз чечено
only then, with the collapse, both of them
ингушетию уже потом при развале обе одна
remained part of Russia, Ingushetia
осталась в составе России Ингушетия
territory.
территория А мы как бы уже вышли
- the land from someone to
оккупировали какую-то землю у кого-то
someone before I don’t know to whom they gave the
кому-то перед не знаю кому они у кого
land from whom the land
Землю чю Землю
We always seemed to have these borders and
передали Мы всегда как бы эти границы
other things between us Russians Well, yes Because
проче между нами русскими Ну да Потому
it didn’t exist like that  Yes, yes,
что она не существовала как такие Да да
I don’t understand now that these people, as
я я не понимаю сейчас что эти люди как
if I’m conveying this to them, too, it’s like
бы я до них тоже это доношу как бы какая
what kind of land? From whom they took it, it doesn’t belong to us, now today they can drive carriages, put us all on carriages and send us home and no one will say a word What kind of land  What are you doing with
слово не скажет Какая земля вы что вы с
each other Goethe
друг другом Гёте
Well, now the level of such
Ну сейчас уровень такой
degradation
деградации К
Unfortunately, why Zakayev Well, I
сожалению почему закаева Ну так жестоко
don’t support him so cruelly because, well, I have
не поддерживаю потому что ну у меня
such a tough position because he, let’s
такая ну жёсткая позиция потому что он
say, is deceiving the people and it’s obvious
скажем так обманывает народ и это видно
And people are moving away So you asked  Yes, why are
И люди отходят Вот вы спросили Да почему
there no other people because all the people
других людей нету потому что все люди
believed him before the full-scale
верили ему до полномасштабного
invasion of the ninety-second year, the
вторжения девяносто второго года
Constitution of his interview for democracy and
Конституцию его интервью за демократию и
among him all the Companions gathered next to him,
среди него рядом с ним собирались все
all those who drowned for freedom and
Соратники все те кто топили за свободу и
gave all their strength and energy to him. They
отдавали все свои силы и энергию ему Они
separately created for themselves what  and here,
отдельно себе создавали что и тут он
before a full-scale invasion, he
перед полномасштабный вторжением
gathers his group in Sweden with
собирает в Швеции свою группировку с
some Bearded
какими-то Бородача
Eurocats with these Well, radicals, and he
еврокат ками с этими Ну радикалами и
comes out and says We now
выходит и говорит Мы теперь
cog I don’t know what this was done with
сог Я не знаю с чем это сделано может
Ukraine should be dragged in by these ISIS fighters from Syria
Украину затащить вот эти игиловцев Сирии
so that they would treat him so loyally,
чтобы они так-то лояльно к нему
believe him, that is, he
отнеслись поверили ему то есть ставку он
did not rely on the ISIS fighters. Well, for example,
сделал на игиловцев не Ну например вот
in Ukraine he fought against Russia, that there
есть в Украине воевал против России то
was this Shini in Syria,
что в Сирии был этот
I know how I
зна нему как
feel about all these Shishani Mishani  as
отношусь к всем этим шишани мишани как
if, well, that is, where
бы ну то есть ты там где религиозная
you don’t perceive the religious component that way,
составляющая ты не воспринимаешь так
of course, of course, I know what this
конечно Конечно я знаю до чего это
has led to. I know what this has led to and
довело Я знаю до чего это доводит и к
what it is leading to now and  what kind of picture
чему это сейчас ведут и какую картину
are presented to the world from this side and from
представляют миру и с этой стороны и с
this side by some bearded men and everyone is for
этой стороны какие-то бородачи и все за
Sharia and everything is for Allah and it’s not clear what
шариат и все за Аллаха и непонятно что
they are squabbling among themselves I
они там короче грызутся между собой Я им
always tell them to gather under Kadyrov
всегда говорю соберитесь под Кадыровым
He is completely according to Islam he does everything
Он полностью по исламу он делает всё
right And nothing  in short, Islam
правильно И ничего короче исламе
is allowed there, someone occupied did not
дозволяется там кто-то оккупировал не
occupy, that is, the question remains
оккупировал то есть тут вопрос Остаётся
only about the authorities, as here, what kind of
только о власти как тут что они какую
culture do they offer, for example, these are the replacements they
культуру например вот эти замен
offer, let’s get out from under and go
предлагают этим выйдем из-под и пойдём
under the Arabs  Yes, I’m better, to be honest. If you
под арабов Да мне лучше если честно Если
compare Russians with Arabs, it’s better,
сравнивать с арабами русские это лучше
although at least some kind of education,
хотя хоть Какая какое-то образование
some kind of access to information of European
какой-то доступ к информации европейской
civilization, even through the Russian language. And what’s
цивилизации хоть и через русский язык А
there in general? Well, Afghanistan, the
там-то что там вообще ну Афганистан
result of this is a direct illustration, the
результат этого вот прямая иллюстрация
clearest illustration is  That is,
самая Ясная иллюстрация это То есть
it turns out now, as I understand it, they are now
получается сейчас я так понимаю сейчас
scaring Chechnya with something. Yes, what if you don’t work
Чечню чем-то пугают Да что если не
with Russia, you will be in a caliphate? Yes,
будете с Россией будете в халифате Да
no, no, no, no, on the contrary,
нет нет нет нет нет наоборот
Russia is completely Well, here, if you
Россия полностью Ну у нас если вы
take  our Republic all over the world, you will
возьмёте нашу Республику во всём мире вы
not find a place where
Не найдёте место где на квадратный метр
so many mosques have been built per square meter and all this is
столько построено мечети и всё это
being built for the Russian budget and all these
строится за российский бюджет и все эти
Islamic institutions, they also
исламские учреждения они тоже
function for the Russian budget, all
функционируют за российский бюджет все
these in the mosques, then you need to install a
эти в мечетях потом же поставить надо
preacher propagandist, they all
проповедника пропагандиста все они
work for the Russian budget  everything seems to be
работают на российский бюджет все как бы
here Russia may be doing something there,
тут Россия может быть и что-то там
but religion is beneficial for them among us,
делает но религия им выгодна среди нас
radicalization because it
радикализация потому что она нас
degrades us, first of all, I watched it recently
деградирует в первую очередь вот недавно
with a Ukrainian blogger, a young
смотрел с украинским блогером молодой
guy too Well, I like his video I
пацан тоже Ну нравится мне его ролик Я
always watched it and he comes across
смотрел его всегда и он ему попадается
some Chechen he tells him there The
какой-то чеченец он ему говорит там
deportation was there back and forth he Well, it’s
Высылка была там туда-сюда он Ну это
also like we’re discussing ourselves, they took it,
тоже мы как бы себя обсуждаем его взяли
it’s like a very good short  there is a 3-4
он как бы очень хорошая короткая там 3-4
minute video of the process itself,
минуты видео сам процесс идёт
an illustration of what it has been reduced to today, he
иллюстрация до чего сегодня доведена он
tells him, this blogger of yours says, Well,
говорит ему говорит этот ваш блогер Ну
you don’t know what they sent you, you don’t
ты не знаешь что у вас выслали ты не
know about genocide, He says this to Me
знаешь про геноцид Он говорит это Мне
what
что перед Аллахом
will help before Allah That is, it is beneficial for Russia, they
поможет То есть это выгодно России нас
don’t scare us, on the contrary,
не пугают наоборот нам со всех сторон
there is beautiful Islam on all sides, good Islam, we
там красивый Ислам хороший Ислам нам
are allowed to pray, build mosques, in short,
дозволяю молиться строить мечети короче
on the contrary, this initiative comes from Russia
наоборот эта инициатива идёт из России
because Russia already Well, they
потому что Россия уже Ну у них архивы
have archives, they already have experience on this
есть у них уже на этом Опыт есть
Tatarstan, there are operations in Afghanistan,
Татарстан вон операции в Афганистане
how many of them are from their Muslim
сколько они из у своих мусульманских
ethnic Muslims, the special forces
этнических мусульман спецназовцы там
overthrew operations there, they carried out all
свергли операции проводили у них весь
this experience, they have with Islam, as if
этот опыт имеется с Исламом как бы также
Dugin also has some kind of lesson he is
есть Дугин может его какой-то урок он
teaching  somehow I don’t know on the wall everything
даёт каким-то не знаю на на стене всё
tells us what we did like I’m
рассказывает мы что сделали типа я ну
sure he’s throwing
уверен что он накидывает конечно пуху
a lot of fluff like we We lost they were
много типа мы Мы проиграли они были
united We went out and divided them through
едиными Мы вышли и разделили их через
religion into Sufis Waha bists
религию на суфистов Ваха бистов
forced them to interrupt yes yes In general
заставили их перебивать да да В общем у
they  we have experience in this, no matter how they scare us,
них в этом опыт имеется как бы нас не
I see we completely agree to go to this
смотрю полностью согласны идти в этот
caliphate, I shout to them, it won’t happen, no one
халифат я им кричу э это не будет никто
in the world will allow you to establish a
в мире не позволит вам устроить на
caliphate in the European part, wake up.
европейской части халифат проснитесь
This is what I think  that they are looking for
Это я считаю что это ищут сейчас
goats now, everyone is
коз все с
looking at this in Dagestan in Dagestan
сча так смотрю в Дагестане в Дагестане
Yes, it seems to me that the beetle is more religious now
Да мне кажется более религиозно сейчас
than in Chena, there has never been and
жука чем чем в чене никогда не было и
never will be, all
никогда не будет все
Dagestan preachers
дагестанские проповедники акцентируют
focus on us If you look at
внимание на нас Если Вы посмотрите
the names I can name Sasitlinsky This is
фамилии могу назвать Саситлинский Это
the most famous Dagestan  radical
самый известный дагестанский радикальный
preacher Zakal gave him citizenship
проповедник закал дал ему гражданство
passport of
паспорт
Ichkeria That is, all of them Imam Shamil is
Ичкерии То есть все они Имам Шамиль это
also the clearest illustration of this path
тоже самая Ясная иллюстрация этого пути
in  In Dagestan they
в Дагестане его
kicked him out, he came to
выгнали он пришёл к
us and sang this Islamic fairy tale,
нам нам напел вот эту сказку исламскую
ours made him a saint. Our
наши из него сделали святым У нас очень
people were very devout throughout history, they
набожный народ был всю историю к этим
took these things of the afterlife very
вещам загробной жизни относился очень
seriously and
серьёзно и
worship us on this and through religion they
набожни нас на этом и через религию до
still continue to do this, he came
сих пор продолжают это делать он пришёл
made us raised to war We fought
сделал нас поднял на войну Мы воевали
now, as if he turns out to be a hero of
сейчас как бы он оказывается герой
Dagestan, but in Dagestan he wouldn’t have
Дагестана но в Дагестане он вообще не бы
Dagestan for him at all, he’s
Дагестан ему там никакого он просто
just an Avar, he’s like that  Yes, he’s
просто аварец он да как бы был Да он
just an Avar, as it were, and now
просто аварец как бы и сейчас то же
they’re emphasizing the same thing on us in Dagestan,
самое они акцентируют на нас в Дагестане
there’s so many nationalities it
там сколько народности у неё никогда не
will never have Dagestan, there’s no such nation there, there aren’t that
будет Дагестан такой нации нет там
many
столько
people there and they don’t understand each other at all,
народа и вообще не понимают они друг
that is, there’s no point there And these people understand that
друга то есть там смысла нету И это
preachers of the Chechen people, as if they are
проповедники чеченски народ как бы он
after all mono, let’s say monoethnic,
как-никак моно скажем так моноэтническое
yes, if according to the new census there are Chechens there,
да там если по новой переписи там чечен
98 no 98 in Ingushetia there are Ingush in my opinion, but
98 нет 98 в ингушети ингушей по-моему а
95% of Chechens in Chechnya yes yes yes And it’s as if it’s
95% чеченцев в Чечне да да да И как бы
easier for everyone to understand, as if
тут легче понимаешь всем одним как бы
you’re talking to one people, you’re working for one
говоришь одному народу работаешь на один
people, but there it won’t
народ а там-то не
work out now, how much now in
получится сейчас насколько сейчас в
Chechnya and Ingushetia there’s more influence of
Чечне и в Ингушетии е ного влияние
teips Yes, as I understand it,  you
тейпов Да вот я так понимаю что у вас
teips structure Well, it’s kind of generic and
тейпов структура Ну как бы родовая так и
uh, there’s still a certain number of them there
ээ ещё определённое количество там
decades ago there are the words Elder
десятков лет назад там слова Старейшина
it was there important there for this and the
это было там важно там для этого и и
tapes among themselves There are also certain
тейпы между собой Там тоже определённые
relations or to what extent these
отношениями или насколько сейчас ещё эти
relations still exist. Well, now they seem to be, let’s
отношения есть Ну сейчас они как бы
say, willingly or unwillingly. The
скажем так вольно или невольно
Russian Empire has, let’s say,
Российская империя нас э скажем так аэ
developed us to national self-awareness. That
развила до национального самосознания То
is, we now have the heat - it’s like your
есть у нас сейчас теп - это как твоё
origin, like identification, nothing more,
происхождение как идентификация не более
we are already all Chechens, you  the Chechens keep
того мы уже все чеченцы ты чеченец всё
asking for the date, the question is
как бы дальше спрашивают дату тут вопрос
not of the Russian Empire, the question is simply
не Российской империи тут вопрос просто
that every nation goes through the stage of this
что каждый народ проходит этап вот этого
development and already from tribes there to Ethnicity
развития и уже там из племён там в Этнос
from ethnic group to nation  goes over Yes, I understand,
из этноса в нацию переходит Да понял
but for example, there is no emphasis on this, this is
а вот например на этом акцента нету это
purely an identification of a Chechen or not a
чисто идентификация чеченец или не
Chechen, which check purely as if with us.
чеченец что провери чисто как бы у нас
We have, as it were, compared from the mountains,
Мы с гор как бы сравнили
spread and our roots go
распространились и корни наши идут
back to the mountains and who is from where yes yes yes And
обратно в гор и кто откуда да да да И
if you go to the mountains  Well, there are roots, it’s already
если в горы у тебя Ну есть корни то уже
clear And it’s there, as it were,
понятно И это есть п как бы
yes. And for example, those people who,
да А например те люди которые вот
as far as the language in some mountainous areas
насколько язык в одних горных местностях
is clear to others, just like in Dagestan,
понятен для других вот как в Дагестане
there can be, yes, conditionally, one mountain, the
там может быть да условно одна гора
other mountain, do not understand each other  you,
вторая гора не понимают друг друга у вас
as far as this is not here, we
насколько это не у нас у нас все
understand everyone, moreover, we and the Ingush
понимают более того мы и с ингушами
all understand each other, but there are a lot of
понимаем все друг друга но очень много
dialects, we also have 10 dialects somewhere,
диалектов у нас тоже 10 где-то диалектов
but we understand each other everything clearly. Well, there
но мы понимаем друг друга все чётко Ну
are dialects everywhere because in any
диалекты всюду есть потому что в любом
nation if  locally, well, let's say that
народе если локально ну скажем это
now there is public education.
сейчас есть государственное Образование
Everyone there has only schools, one TV,
у всех там одни школы один телевизор
only textbooks. Yes, and it is a standard. And
одни учебники Да и оно есть стандарт А
before it was you live. Even
раньше было ты живёшь Тут даже вот у нас
here in Ukraine, I have Podolia. Yes, the dialect is
тут в Украине у меня Подолье Да говор
moving away.  40 km there is a different dialect. Yes,
один отъезжает 40 км там другой говор Да
you have it because the terrain is no longer
Во у вас из-за того что более не
flat. And as if the Mountain people
равнинная местность А как бы Горная люди
mixed less and less because, for
меньше да меньше перемешивали потому что
example, the Kazakhs in general, and there,
например вот у казаха вообще да там
for example, the steppe, and there
например степь да и перемещение
was quite a movement of the population; Broad Yes, these are
населения довольно была Широкая Да вот
people who are people  who in the Carpathians
люди которые люди которые в Карпатах
live in our mountains, and they also
живут у нас в горах да у них тоже уже
have a better saddle, and therefore
более седло получается да и поэтому у
they have preserved some local
них сохранились какие-то локальные
traditions there, for example, specifically for
традиции там например именно для вот
this region, but in the neighboring one it’s completely
этого региона А в соседнем уже совсем
different, well,  You can’t compare us with Dagestan
по-другому ну с дагестаном нас сравнить
because there are about 40, somewhere around 30
нельзя потому что там около 40 где-то 30
there are different Yes, different nationalities Yes,
там разные Да разные национальности Да
each Empire dragged its own there,
каждая Империя туда тащила своих
slaughtered the locals and dragged its own as if the
вырезала местных и тащила своих как бы
Arabs
арабы
there, except it turns out Well, if you
туда там кроме получается Ну если там
look at the fact that the Kumyks are like the Turks and the
смотреть что кумыки Да как тюрки а
rest are essentially all  there are autochthons there,
остальные по сути все автохтоны там вот
if there are Lezgins there, who are the Dargins, varnish,
если там лезгины Кто там даргинцы лак
they are not like any
они ж все ну не похожи ни на каких
others, they are all autochthonous there, well, I don’t
других они все автохтонные там ну я не
know about everyone, but yes, something like that yes  it’s
знаю насчёт всех но да примерно так да
just that even all these nationalities are
просто я даже эти все национальности
a lot Yes, I know the Dargins, as if they are
много Да я знаю даргинцев как бы они к
closer to us Well, with us, as if we
нам ближе Ну у них у нас как бы если
go deep there at 34,000, it’s as if we are alone,
идти вглубь там на 34000 как бы мы одни
as if in the language in linguistics in DNA it’s a
как бы на языке на лингвистике в ДНК это
mustache
усе
and varnish and we’d be damned  irt
и лак и мы нах бы ирт
Georgians we are like autochthons just like the
грузины мы как бы автохтоны точно
rest I don’t know I just haven’t studied
остальных Я не знаю просто я не изучал
them and the Adygs of course
их и Адыги конечно
also the Adygs are Circassians this is a completely
тоже Адыги - это черкес это совсем
different group Yes I mean
другая группа Да я имею в виду автохтоны
like autochthons  what about the autochthons in the Caucasus? By
как бы а что автохтоны на Кавказе
the way, in Georgia. I know in Georgia
Да кстати в Грузии Я знаю в Грузии
there are
есть дан
words, they are quite specific, they seem to be.
слы они довольно специфические они как
And you’re talking about Pankisi. Do they
бы по А ты про панкиси Да они
maintain some kind of relations with Chechnya
поддерживают с чечнёй какие-то отношения
or not, well, I’m
или нет ну я
not from there. Well, there too, if you
не там оттуда Воже там тоже вот если
take it  general picture Yes, among the Chechens, the
взять общую картину Да среди чеченцев
Bansky Gorge is, well, let’s say the most
банское ущелье - это ну самое скажем так
radical place in terms of Islam, where
радикальное место в плане Ислама там
people generally follow Islam for the
люди вообще на исламе
last 10 years, a little bit. Previously,
послед 10 лет чуть-чуть Раньше у нас
even when  this
даже когда распространился этот
radicalism has spread among them, and they are also culturally our
радикализм у них ВС ещ они культурно наш
Chechen old way of life and not even the dialect
чеченский старый быт и у не и диалект
has been preserved. But today there is a general
всё это сохранялся Но сегодня там вообще
catastrophe with this Islamization, by the way, in the
катастрофа с этой исламизации кстати в
ISIS in Syria, which is
иги в Сирии которы
exactly there, yes, yes, I kind of think that
уе именно там да да я как бы считаю что
this is no offense to the Georgians  This is an
это не в обиду грузинам это
imperial policy. I think it’s so
имперская политика Я считаю так
difficult for the people, it’s like a reproach for the people, but the
непростым народом как бы народу упрёк но
imperial policy works as if, well,
политика имперская работает как бы ну
well, you know, everyone will
это ну сам понимаешь это каждый будет
do it, as if yes, it’s in the interests of every
делать как бы да это в интересах каждого
people  look, you’re like the night
народа как смотри Вот такое ты как ночи
Yes, you seem to understand these local matters, yes,
Да ты вот вроде там в местных этих делах
Kadyrov is already
понимаешь да Кадыров уже всё-таки
somewhere and there,
где-то и там и поро есть Ясно
and it’s time to be. It’s clear that he’ll be gone for two or three years, conditionally.
чтото год два-три условно и его не
Yes,
станет Да
uh, how do you assess if he does  the
Ээ как ты оцениваешь если вот будет
Russian Empire will still survive, and
сохраниться ещё Российская империя Да и
Chechnya will be part of the Russian Empire, what
Чечня в составе Российской империи что
will be who will be Kadyrov’s successor?
будет кто будет преемником Кадырова
What kind of movements are there for this,
Какие вообще на это есть там движения
or will there be some kind of
или будет какая-то из-за
conflict because of this within the Chechen elite? Well,
этого конфликт внутри Элит чеченских Ну
inside  there is no Chechen elite. There the
внутри чеченской никакой элиты нету Там
entire Elite has been completely
вся Элита уничтожена полностью под
destroyed and the most insignificant one has been chosen, let’s
корень и выбран как бы самый ничтожный
say, like Pushilin’s son. Yes, yes, it’s
скажем так как пушилин сынок Да да это
like, well, this is an imperial policy, you know,
как бы ну это политика имперская знаешь
don’t create political
не создавать себе политических
competitors for yourself, they take the real rednecks
конкурентов берут самое настоящее [__]
and put them, as it were, in an occupied
и ставят его как бы да на оккупированном
area  as if and if for me personally
местностью как бы и если для меня лично
Kadyrov, well, Kadyrov will die, no matter what
Кадыров как бы ну умрёт Кадыров что бы с
happens to him, they will find there, I don’t know, but
ним не случилось найдут там не знаю но
or someone else There, as it were, Differences  no, in
или ещ кого-то Там как бы Разницы нету в
principle it’s just a tool, as it were, but
принципе это просто инструмент как бы но
perhaps I think it’s out of hatred for us,
возможно я считаю из-за ненависти к нам
because they understand that
э поскольку Они понимают что наш
they haven’t completely destroyed our rebellious spirit.
бунтарский дух Они до конца не
I hope it never
уничтожили Я надеюсь никогда не
will, as long as at least one
уничтожит пока останется хотя бы один
Chechen remains, and purely to take revenge on us, they’re there
чеченец и чисто чтобы мстить нам они там
again  what kind of weird thing is it
опять же какую какую как что-то на чудят
seems to me like there is a war between them We
мне кажется между ними типа война Мы
will remove Kadyrov now there are already
сейчас Кадырова уберём там уже идут
conversations going on we are there E I don’t remember his name
разговоры мы там Э я не помню его имя
in short he is
короче он
LPR
лнр
some tall so skinny
какой-то высокий такой худой какой-то
propagandist Ardent LPR or DPR I don’t remember,
пропагандист Ярый лнр или ДНР не помню я
well, the permanent face there is shining, we are there
ну постоянное лицо там светящееся мы там
Kadyrov wants to make the whole of Russia Chechnya,
Кадыров хочет всю Россию сделать чечнёй
but no matter how we Russians don’t allow this, we will
но как бы мы русские этого не дадим Мы в
establish order in Chechnya. There are already
Чечне установим порядок коче уже идут
conversations going on like they themselves did Kadyrov
разговоры типа сами сделали Кадырова
now and they will now be angels
теперь и они сейчас будут ангелами
who will
которые
deliver  yes And look at the picture, Gordon
избавят да И картину смотри са Гордон
Mordon Now I’m watching in Ukraine Yes, too,
мордон Сейчас я смотрю в Украине Да тоже
this Zelensky in the team
арахамия вот этот Зеленского в команде
who stands and speaks is an aramic  the Chechens
который стоит и говорит там чеченцы
seized a power plant of some kind and an
захватили электростанцию какая-то там да
AGS something. There they can demand
АГС что-то Там они могут потребовать
independence. The Kadyrovites seized something there,
независимость кадыровцы там что-то
like and then the Pope leaves,
захватили типа и потом уходит Папа
says the butches there, that they did
Римский говорит бучи там то что сделали
it not in Russian culture, the most
это не в русской культуре там самые
cruel ones are the Chechens and Buryats. The Pope
жестокие стя чеченцы и буряты Папа
on  the whole world, that is, they have
Римский на весь мир то есть они создали
now created a picture in the world and in Europe
сейчас в мире картину такую и в Европе
that, like Kadyrov and the Chechens, the Kadyrovites
что типа Кадыров и чеченцы кадыровцы
attacked Ukraine and Zelensky cannot with
напали на Украину и Зеленский не может с
him  together with America and NATO to deal
ним вместе с Америкой и НАТО справиться
with Kadyrov, such a picture was made by Gordon;
с Кадыровым такую картину сделали Гордон
Kadyrov’s enemy is generally separated there;
вообще разошёлся там враг Кадырова
Kadyrov’s personal enemy is what kind of
личный враг Кадырова какой враг Кады
enemy of Kady; a Chechen can only be an enemy
врагом чеченец может быть только
of Russia; how can a Chechen be an enemy of a
России как может быть чеченец врагом
dog? Well, the dog bit you, as the
собаки Ну Собака покусала тебя как
proverb tells us; Yes, the difference between
говорят нам пословица Да разница между
a dog and a Lion is a dog.  he looks at the
собакой и Львом собака смотрит там на
stick there and Lev looks at the one who threw this stick
палку а Лев на того кто эту палку
here, like a tool, look at how you
кинул тут как бы инстру смотри как ты
react here  there is a battalion named after
относишься вот есть это батальон имени
Sheikh Mansur, but it’s not like on the Russian side, we are in
Шейха Мансура но не то что со стороны
Ukraine, do you know people from there? Well, I’ll
украи знаешь ли людей оттуда Ну это как
say this honestly, before I
бы честно скажу вот до я Иса мунаева
fully 100% supported Isa Munayeva, even though he’s not a
полностью 100% поддерживал хоть он не
Muslim. Even though I don’t like Islam and in
мусульманин Хоть я не люблю ислам и ни в
no way do I not  I accept Muna was
какой его мере Не приемлю Муна был
a man in a million, as if among us there are
человеком на миллион как бы среди нас
probably no such people left now.
наверное сейчас таких уже и не осталось
It was such a
Это был такой чело
person, VM
баль ВМ
kind of supported them, drowned them for them, and
их как бы поддерживал топил за них и
today, as if Sheikh Mansura, I
сегодня как бы Шейх Мансура я ничего
can’t say anything negative for them  I can’t say, but I
негативного не могу за них сказать но и
also can’t say that I support it,
как бы поддерживаю тоже не могу сказать
because the example they are passing on to the youth is
потому что молодёжи пример который Они
Yes, all this beard, all this
передают Да вся эта борода вся эта
religiosity. I don’t like it, I
религиозность Мне она не нравится ничего
can’t say anything bad about
не могу сказать плохого про
Muslim, as if they
Муслима как бы и раз они сегодня в
are working today in the interests of Ukraine, they are helping you,
интересах Украины работают помогают вам
then for me.  as if this is also good, but
то для меня как бы тоже это хорошо а
because here, in principle, if Ukraine doesn’t
потому что тут в принципе если не
hold out, then there
выстоит Украина то ни про какую там
won’t be any talk about any independent Keri now, but
независимую Кери сейчас не буде а
on the contrary, if Russia gets hit in the teeth
наоборот если России дадут по зубам Да
Yes, it’s starting to crack in Syria, it’s
вот она начинает трещать в Сирии
cracked Yes
треснула Да
Russian politics Yes, somewhere in Moldova
Российская политика Да где-то в Молдове
they tried to promote their own, too,
они там пробовали продвигать своё тоже
crack, yes, that is, and I think that it will
трещ да то есть и я думаю что оно
crack in the Caucasus sooner or later Yes,
треснет и на Кавказе рано или поздно Да
I kind of crack, it will crack in any way,
я как бы треснет оно по-любому треснет
I’m all talking to the Russian empire, I give the
я все говор русским империи привожу
example of Egypt
пример Египет
Sumeria Where  They are Where
шумери Где они Где
the gold is, the ruins are just left and there are
золото развалины только остались и
no people left there either in Rome Yes, the
народа тоже не осталось там Риме Да
Italians are left, there are no Egyptians, there are
итальянцы остались египтян нету шумер
no Sumerians and there are no other empires, and the question for
нету и другие империи нету и вопрос
the Russians is whether they will remain after this or
русским останутся ли они после это или
just collapsed,
просто развали как
as it were, I have a normal community.
бы кон у меня ну нормальное сообщество
We recently started but are already developing, as
Недавно мы начали но уже развиваемся как
if we convey to people that during the collapse we were
бы доносим до людей что при развале были
ready and let’s say the table where we are
готовы и скажем так стол куда мы
tied. Where We all pray and
привязаны Куда Мы все молимся и
worship so that it stands in Chechnya and not
поклоняемся чтобы он стоял в Чечне а не
in Saudi Arabia or  in Turkey or in
в Саудовской Аравии или в Турции или в
Persia or somewhere else in Catholicism in
Персии или ещё где-то в католицизме в
Rome in Chechnya, well, these processes were also
Риме в Чечне ну эти эти процессы также
going on in the Christian Church, yes, that is, it
христианская церков шла да то есть там
was there. Just like in Islam now, there
было Вот как как в исламе сейчас вот там
is this stone Cab  or whatever it is, here he
есть этот камень Каб или как там вот он
stands And everyone should go to him cla Yes,
стоит И все должны к нему ехать кла Да
do the same Vatican Yes, the Vatican,
так же сделать Ватикан Да чтот Ватикан
almost everything you are there is the Holy Pope, in short,
чуть ли не всё ты там Святой папа короче
and this And against the background of this, and against the background of this,
и это И на фоне этого да на фоне этого
then yes, Protestantism Well How it
потом вот да протестантство ж Как
arose Yes, in fact  they, uh, came out
возникло Да по сути они ээ выступали Вот
with ideas like yours, yes, that
тоже вот с такими идеями Как у вас да то
is, yes. For example, we are Christians. Yes, but
есть да Мы например мы христиане Да но
we are not for the Vatican. And we are there for Christ. Yes, and there are a
мы не за Ватикан А мы там за Христа Да и
lot of such movements, yes,
очень много да таких течений да
because, well, naturally, let’s say the
получается потому что ну природно скажем
development of this religion  it’s so bad that these
развитие этой религии пошло что ну эти
peoples, what do we have to do with some pope,
народы Да что мы имеем к какому-то папе
whom we owe there? Moreover,
э которому мы должны там э Тем более это
all this has also degraded, yes, when
всё тоже деградировала да Когда вот эти
all these popes and so on turned into gold. In short,
все э папы и так далее в золото Короче
they almost swam there. Yes, you
они там купались чуть ли не Да ты
preach it like  right now Patriarch
проповедует оно как вот сейчас Патриарх
Kirill, conditionally, these are also the same things
Кирилл условно тоже вот такие же вещи
as Europe Yes, Europe just
как бы и Европа Да Европа просто эти
went through these processes, that is, in Europe it
процессы прошла да то есть в Европе
seems like even in those Catholic
вроде как бы даже в католических тех
countries there are yes there, well, formally this is already,
странах есть да там ну формально это уже
that is, the papal throne does not have such
то есть папский престол не имеет такого
influences That is,
влияния То есть
he is dada, yes, it’s more like a
он дада да это как бы больше уже как
tradition,
традиция как бы
yes, yes, I understand, but the question is just here,
уже да да я понимаю но просто тут вопрос
you know, what will we remain after all
знаешь в чём останемся ли мы после всех
these
этих
questions, so that we and our culture
вопросов чтобы мы и наша культура
remain, our ancestors went underground for generations
осталась наши предки поколениями шли под
and so that we are here  they could do it all so easily
землю и чтоб мы тут всё так просто
and they became
змогли рукой и стали
Arabs of Magomed of no memory of kinship, as
арабами Магомеда непомнящего родства как
if that’s
бы вот такое себе
the case. That’s the question, as if the Arabs are Islam,
дело Вот в чём вопрос как бы арабы Ислам
it’s a little different from
он же чуть-чуть отличается от
Christianity. Christianity, as it were, is
христианства Христианстве как бы
a nationality, it’s
национальность она как бы там
more or less there
более-менее
no don’t look there is an Armenian national
не не смотри есть армянская национальная
church Yes there is not like that look here in
церковь Да есть не так смотри вот в
Christianity the same idea
христианстве такая же идея
International what is there no how is there
Интернациональная что там нет как там
a Bible no Elina Nevre Jews there Nigo
Библии нет ни Элина невре иудеи там Ниго
yes that is also its time Yes that was also It’s
да то есть и своё время Да это тоже было
like global studies and
Вот такой как бы глобалистика да и
look  with names too, yes that’s how it is
посмотри с именами тоже да вот как
now in the Islamic world in Arabic ina there
сейчас в исламском мире арабским ина там
Muhammad is yes That’s how you say yes
Мухаммад это да Вот как ты говоришь да
unusual for you and also for us yes for
несвойственный вам да также и у нас да
example here My name is
например вот Меня зовут Андрей Да я
Andrey Yes, I am a Slav Yes, I am from Ukraine, but they called me a Greek name Yes, why because Christianity came Yes they started Yes, Greek names, Jewish names, Latin names come out and it also changed, yes, that is, we had a place there there was Boleslav there Vladimir and so on Yes they began to become these church names, yes, some of the Slavic ones who were there remained, which they accepted that once he was a prince, he baptized Rus', all he is now there is the Holy Equal-to-the-Apostles, for example, yes, and this too, yes  cultural sphere in many
да культурный шар ээ во многих
European nations, this
европейских народах вот эта
Christianization, it has lost this
христианизация она ээ утратила вот эту
sort of primary tradition Yes, in the good
как бы первичную традицию Да в хорошем
sense of the word, yes Uh-huh Uh-huh Uh-huh And that
смысле этого слова да Угу Угу Угу И та
too with the Arabs Yes, if you now
также с арабами Да вот если сейчас
look at how the Arabs
посмотреть там как показывают арабы
live there Egypt Arabs Tunisia Arabs Maro everything
живут Египет арабы Тунис арабы Маро всё
all Arabs Yes uh But this was where the Arab
всё арабы Да ээ Но это было где арабская
empire was widespread but these were
империя была распространена но это были
different peoples Yes different peoples of which
разные народы Да разные народы которых
simply Arabs Zro through religion through
просто Араби Зро через религию через
lost their language but he  after all, Islam is
потеряли язык но он вс-таки Ислам он
more radical, it is not only culturally
более радикальный он не только культурно
but also genetically enriching, that is, the
но и генетически обогащает то есть самом
Koran sura itself
Коране суре чем чет аяте
is allowed to engage in copulation with a
дозволяется заниматься совокупляться с
captured woman even if
женщиной захваченной в плен даже если
she is married, and as it were, it is more
она замужняя и как бы тут как бы более
radical here and you see these people
радикально и вот видишь вот эти люди
who  the people called them today the Arabs do not
которые народ назвал их сегодня арабы не
recognize they have lost their language and
признают они свой яз потеряли и культуру
their culture And in general our language
свою потеряли А у нас вообще язык не
has no relatives, if it is lost it
имеет родственников он если потеряется
will be impossible to
Его невозможно будет
reconstruct a more critical
реконструировать более критическая
situation, as it were, well, I have Well  you understand
ситуация как бы ну у меня Ну понимаешь
your demons in your head
свои демоны в голове
How I won’t Okay let’s run ok
Как не буду Хорошо давай побегу хоро
good analysis was good luck Thank you to
хороший разбор был удачи Спасибо до
the party
побачення
so yes it was interesting we turned to
так да интересный у нас был повороти на
stream with Finnish lag we met an
стрими с лагом финским встретили
interesting interlocutor we changed it so oh
интересного собеседника поменяли це так
I’ll eat further write nay Telegram directly at
ой ем дальше пись най Telegram прямо
the same time axis VN
зараз ось ВН
apok tse duzhe  and very respectfully YouTube took
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the skarg ODS to your ban and even more
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
richly  I don’t show videos to people at all times, I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for this purpose, so that the
показуе информация про стримы тому для
Mali operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
is written directly at once, and Popik is there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegrams okrim video, shchezh Tsikava and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
Korisna information and we are guilty of you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
trimati postiyny operational link,
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
regardless of that, show you about  tse
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
letter
пись а